<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alexandre M. S. Machado on Alexandre M. S. Machado</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Alexandre M. S. Machado on Alexandre M. S. Machado</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Homophily around specialized foraging underlies dolphin social preferences</title>
      <link>/publication/machado-et-al-2019-biol-lett/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/machado-et-al-2019-biol-lett/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Individual traits affect the society of bottlenose dolphins that forages cooperatively with artisanal fishermen</title>
      <link>/project/master-thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/master-thesis/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;master-s-degree-research-project-apr-2016-may-2018&#34;&gt;Master&amp;rsquo;s degree research project (Apr 2016 - May 2018)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was supervised by &lt;a href=&#34;http://buscatextual.cnpq.br/buscatextual/visualizacv.do?metodo=apresentar&amp;amp;id=K4773176H3&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Dr. Fábio Gonçalves Daura-Jorge&lt;/a&gt; and co-supervised by &lt;a href=&#34;https://cantor.weebly.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Dr. Mauricio Cantor&lt;/a&gt;, with a 2-year scholarship provided by the Brazilian Ministry of Education (CAPES).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Laguna, southern Brazil, some individuals of a bottlenose dolphin population (&lt;em&gt;Tursiops truncatus&lt;/em&gt;) forage in cooperation with artisanal fishermen. The social structure of this dolphin population is coupled to this specialized foraging tactic, in which social modules are defined by individuals that often or rarely forage in cooperation with fishermen. However, other individual traits might also underlie this social structure, but their effects are yet to be quantified. In this study, we aim to tease apart the contributions of other ecological, biological and behavioral traits in modulating the social relationships in different foraging and non-foraging contexts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;funding&#34;&gt;Funding&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2016: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.marinemammalscience.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Society for Marine Mammalogy (USA)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
2017: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.animalbehaviorsociety.org/web/index.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Animal Behaviour Society (USA)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;media-coverage&#34;&gt;Media coverage&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nationalgeographic.com/animals/2019/04/dolphins-fishermen-brazil-culture/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;National Geographic&lt;/a&gt;, written by &lt;a href=&#34;https://ericatennenhouse.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Erica Tennenhouse&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;em&gt;These fishermen-helping dolphins have their own culture&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://phys.org/news/2019-04-dolphins-fishermen-meals.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Phys.org&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Dolphins who help fishermen found to also hang out together between meals&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Artisanal fishers’ perceptions of the ecosystem services derived from a dolphin-human cooperative fishing interaction in southern Brazil</title>
      <link>/project/honours-thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/honours-thesis/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;honour-s-thesis-research-project-2013-2015&#34;&gt;Honour&amp;rsquo;s thesis research project (2013 - 2015)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was supervised by &lt;a href=&#34;http://lattes.cnpq.br/2618273220757185&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Dr. Nivaldo Peroni&lt;/a&gt; and co-supervised by &lt;a href=&#34;http://lattes.cnpq.br/7945592097983692&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Dr. Fábio Gonçalves Daura-Jorge&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://lattes.cnpq.br/9760761455546946&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;MSc. Dannielli Firme Herbst&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Incorporating the perception and attitudes of key stakeholders into conservation management can contribute to biodiversity conservation and has the potential to resolve human-wildlife conflicts. To this end, there is scope to enhance conservation outcomes by improving the capture and analysis of stakeholders perceptions and translating these into the management decision making process. Here, an ecosystem services approach (i.e. the benefits people obtain from nature) is used to assess the societal benefits derived from a specialized and rare behavior exhibited by bottlenose dolphins (&lt;em&gt;Tursiops truncatus gephyreus&lt;/em&gt;) that cooperatively forage with artisanal fishers in Laguna, southern Brazil. From interviews, we identified ecosystem services based on the perception of artisanal fishers who take part in this interaction. The perceived benefits of cooperative fishing with dolphins, identified from these interviews, were grouped into eight ecosystem services assigned into cultural (n = 7) and provisioning (n = 1) related services. The results showed that experienced fishers were more likely to identify multiple and diverse ecosystem services, while fishers exposed to tourists tended to focus on tourism and recreation leisure as benefits from fishing with dolphins. Our findings show that the human component is a key element in this system and support the proposal that future conservation decisions and management plans of Laguna&amp;rsquo;s bottlenose dolphins should involve artisanal fishers to be more effective. Our findings indicate that an ecosystem services approach could help decision-makers to better integrate social, economic and cultural aspects of human-wildlife interactions into conservation and management strategies for wildlife in a wider context.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Artisanal fishers&#39; perceptions of the ecosystem services derived from a dolphin-human cooperative fishing interaction in southern Brazil</title>
      <link>/publication/machado-et-al-2019-ocma/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/machado-et-al-2019-ocma/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Policy</title>
      <link>/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/privacy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
