<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Alexandre M. S. Machado</title>
    <link>/tags/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Alexandre M. S. Machado</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Individual traits affect the society of bottlenose dolphins that forages cooperatively with artisanal fishermen</title>
      <link>/project/master-thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/master-thesis/</guid>
      <description>Master&amp;rsquo;s degree research project (Apr 2016 - May 2018) I was supervised by Dr. Fábio Gonçalves Daura-Jorge and co-supervised by Dr. Mauricio Cantor, with a 2-year scholarship provided by the Brazilian Ministry of Education (CAPES).
Abstract In Laguna, southern Brazil, some individuals of a bottlenose dolphin population (Tursiops truncatus) forage in cooperation with artisanal fishermen. The social structure of this dolphin population is coupled to this specialized foraging tactic, in which social modules are defined by individuals that often or rarely forage in cooperation with fishermen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Artisanal fishers’ perceptions of the ecosystem services derived from a dolphin-human cooperative fishing interaction in southern Brazil</title>
      <link>/project/honours-thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/honours-thesis/</guid>
      <description>Honour&amp;rsquo;s thesis research project (2013 - 2015) I was supervised by Dr. Nivaldo Peroni and co-supervised by Dr. Fábio Gonçalves Daura-Jorge and MSc. Dannielli Firme Herbst.
Abstract: Incorporating the perception and attitudes of key stakeholders into conservation management can contribute to biodiversity conservation and has the potential to resolve human-wildlife conflicts. To this end, there is scope to enhance conservation outcomes by improving the capture and analysis of stakeholders perceptions and translating these into the management decision making process.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>